<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rfc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="rfc2629.xsd"
  ipr="none" docName="draft-rcartwright-amwa-rfc-1">
  <front>
    <title abbrev="RESTful AS-02 API">
      A RESTful Application Programming Interface for AMWA's AS-02
    </title>
    <author initials="R.I." surname="Cartwright" fullname="Richard I. Cartwright">
      <organization>Quantel Ltd.</organization>
      <address>
      	<postal>
      	  <street>31 Turnpike Road</street>
      	  <city>Newbury</city>
      	  <code>RG14 2NX</code>
      	  <country>UK</country>
      	</postal>
      	<phone>+44 7785 771568</phone>
      	<email>Richard.Cartwright@quantel.com</email>
      	<uri>http://www.quantel.com/</uri>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="AMWA">
        Advanced Media Workflow Association, Inc.
      </organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>436 N. Westfield Road</street>
          <city>Madison</city>
          <region>WI</region>
          <code>53717</code>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
        <phone>+1-608-513-5992</phone>
        <email>barbara.main@amwa.tv</email>
        <uri>http://www.amwa.tv/</uri>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date month="May" year="2015"/>
    <area>Interface specifications</area>
    <workgroup>RFC process committee</workgroup>
    <keyword>REST</keyword>
    <keyword>AS-02</keyword>
    <keyword>API</keyword>
    <keyword>MXF</keyword>
    <keyword>versioning</keyword>    
    <abstract >
      <t>A RESTful API (AMWA interface specification) for the creation, reading, updating and deleting of AS-02 bundles and the 
      assets that they contain. The aim of the API is that it makes the use of and testing of AS-02-based applications more efficient 
      by separating the concerns of storing and retrieving media data from the mechanics of the underlying store, enabling the originally 
      intended versioning workflows. </t>
    </abstract>
    <note title="RFC Process Committee expriment">
      <t>This document is under development as part of an experimental process to produce the first AMWA request for comments.</t>
    </note>
  </front>
  <middle>
    <section anchor="intro" title="Introduction">
      <section title="Overview">
        <t>A RESTful API (AMWA interface specification) for the creation, reading, updating and deleting of AS-02 bundles and the assets 
        that they contain. The aim of the API is that it makes the use of and testing of AS-02-based applications more efficient by 
        separating the concerns of storing and retrieving media data from the mechanics of the underlying store, enabling the originally 
        intended versioning workflows. The API will provide:
        <list>
          <t>an interface that abstracts developers from the detail of working with the underlying byte formats of MXF files and maintaining 
          manifest files, loosely coupling the AS-02 application and store;</t>
          <t>a means to dynamically change bundles by growing files, adding new audio tracks, working with vendor-specific data in the extras 
          folder;</t>
          <t>support for common read and write operations over units of essence - such as frames, samples and timecodes - and metadata 
          structures, providing a stateless view into what is stored inside the MXF files.</t>
        </list>
        A common interface at this level provides a new media-rich interoperability point between applications and storage, where that storage 
        can be interchanged between local disk, tiered storage, distributed file systems (e.g. GPFS) or object storage. As a REST API, the interface 
        can take advantage of Internet-scaling techniques such as web caches and/or load balancing.
        </t>
      </section>
      <section title="Document structure">
        <t>This document ...</t>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section title="Specification Method">
    	<t>The API is specified and documented using the RAML specification, as documented by <eref target="http://raml.org/spec.html"/>.
    	The specification is contained in <eref target="as02.raml"/>.</t>
    	
    	<t>The RAML specification makes use of XML schema and JSON LD schema.</t>
    </section>
    <section title=""></section>
  </middle>
  <back>
    <references>
      <reference anchor="refs.AS-02">
        <front>
          <title></title>
          <author></author>
          <date/>
        </front>
      </reference>
    </references>
  </back>
</rfc>
